This is it Folks!
Coonskin is a drama, animation, comedy film directed by Ralph Bakshi.
A multi-layered satire of race relations in America.
Live-action sequences of a prison break bracket the animated tale of Brother Rabbit, Brother Bear, and Preacher Fox, who
rise to the top of the crime ranks in Harlem by going up against a con-man, a racist cop, and the Mafia.
Randy / Brother Rabbit (voice), played by Philip Michael Thomas.
Sampson / Brother Bear (voice), played by Barry White.
Preacherman / Preacher Fox (voice), played by Charles Gordone.
Pappy / Old Man Bone (voice), played by Scatman Crothers.
Clown (voice), played by Danny Rees.
Referee (voice), played by Buddy Douglas.
Coonskin is a 1975 American live-action/animated satirical crime film written and
directed by Ralph Bakshi, adapted from the Uncle Remus folk tales.
The narrative concerns three anthropomorphic characters, Br'er Rabbit, referred to as Brother Rabbit,
Br'er Fox, referred to as Preacher Fox, and Br'er Bear, referred to as Brother Bear.
They rise to the top of the organized crime racket in Harlem, encountering corrupt law enforcement, con artists,
and the Mafia, in a satire of both racism within the Hollywood film system, and America itself.
The film stars Philip Thomas, Charles Gordone, Barry White, and Scatman Crothers,
all of whom appear in both live-action and animated sequences.
Originally produced under the titles Harlem Nights and Coonskin No More...
at Paramount Pictures, Coonskin encountered controversy before its original theatrical
release, when the Congress of Racial Equality accused the film of being racist.
When the film was released, Bryanston gave it limited
distribution and it initially received mixed reviews.
Later re-released under the titles Bustin' Out and Street Fight, Coonskin has since been re-appraised, recontextualizing the film as the
condemnation of racism that the director intended, rather than a product of a racist imagination, as its detractors had claimed.
A New York Times review said, "Coonskin could be Ralph Bakshi's masterpiece."
Bakshi has stated that he considers Coonskin to be his best film.
The film explores themes of bunny, sexuality, black
activist, racism, adult animation.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.